<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC
  "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<!--
    Copyright 2014-2022 Bloomreach B.V. (https://www.bloomreach.com)

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the  "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS"
    BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Architecture (External Document Field Picker)</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Architecture (External Document Field Picker)">
      <subsection name="Overview">
        <p>
          In Hippo CMS authoring application, the <strong>External Document Picker Base for Field Picker</strong>
          plugin and <strong>External Picker Folder Context Menu</strong> plugins are installed.
          Then you can configure field(s) in document template bootstrap files (a.k.a Hippo CMS 'namespace'),
          or you can configure folder workflow configurations for a custom folder context menu item.
          So, when you are editing a document or working on a folder in CMS authoring application,
          you will see those being displayed by this plugin.
        </p>
        <p>
          Each document field or folder workflow must be configured with a custom domain-specific
          <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> implementation class name.
        </p>
        <p>
          This plugin component instantiates your <code>ExternalSearchServiceFacade</code> class and invokes it like the following:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            First of all, an <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance is in the same lifecycle of this plugin.
            In case <strong>External Document Picker Base for Field Picker</strong> is used,
            whenever a document (of the configured namespace) is opened or edited, the plugin will be instantiated.
            In case <strong>External Picker Folder Context Menu</strong> is used,
            whenever the folder context menu is pulled down on a folder (of the configured folder workflow type),
            the plugin will be instantiated.
            And the plugin will instantiate an <code>ExternalSearchServiceFacade</code> instance.
            When the document is closed, this plugin and the <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance will be destroyed.
          </li>
          <li>
            When the plugin is instantiated, the plugin invokes the <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance to retrieve
            the currently-selected domain-specific external documents from the currently-viewed/edited CMS document or the selected folder node in the context.
          </li>
          <li>
            When the plugin needs to display the linked external documents (e.g, title),
            it invokes the <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> with the current document context.
            The <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> should give a proper title or description string values for your domain-specific document object to the plugin.
          </li>
          <li>
            The <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance is invoked from the External Document Field Browser Dialog in order to
            search domain-specific external documents and display document information such as title, description and icon in the dialog.
          </li>
          <li>
            The dialog iterates the searched external document items to show the result in either
            the default <strong><i>Flat List View</i></strong> or <strong><i>Tree List View</i></strong> table
            by reading title, description and optionally icon image link from each external document item.
          </li>
          <li>
            When a user selects single or multiple items in the table view and clicks on the OK button,
            the dialog saves the selections by invoking <code>ExternalDocumentServiceFacade#setFieldExternalDocuments()</code> method.
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          Here's an architectural overview. As you can see, you can care of only your custom <code>ExternalDocumentServiceFacade</code>
          implementation class with simple configurations for a specific document field without having to spend
          much effort on CMS Document Editor UI customization by yourself.
        </p>
        <img src="../images/exdocpickerbase-archview.png" alt="Architectural View" />
        <p>
          Here's a sequence diagram showing the interactions:
        </p>
        <img src="../images/exdocpickerbase-field-sequence.png" alt="Sequence Diagram" />
        <p>
          See <a href="../xref/index.html">Javadocs</a> for detail about the <a href="../xref/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a>.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
