<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC
  "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
  "http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<!--
    Copyright 2014 Hippo

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the  "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS"
    BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Architecture (External Document Field Picker)</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Architecture (External Document Field Picker)">
      <subsection name="Overview">
        <p>
          In Hippo CMS UI, the <strong>External Document Picker Base for Field Picker</strong> plugin is installed.
          Then you can configure field(s) in document template bootstrap XML files (a.k.a Hippo CMS 'namespace').
          So, when you are editing a document in CMS UI, you will see those configured fields displayed by this plugin.
        </p>
        <p>
          Each field must be configured with a custom domain-specific <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> implementation class name.
        </p>
        <p>
          This plugin component instantiates your <code>ExternalSearchServiceFacade</code> class and invokes it in the following cases:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            First of all, an <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance is in the same lifecycle of this plugin.
            When a document is opened or edited, this plugin will be instantiated, and this plugin will instantiate an
            <code>ExternalSearchServiceFacade</code> instance.
            When the document is closed, this plugin and the <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance will be destroyed.
          </li>
          <li>
            When this plugin is instantiated, the plugin invokes the <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance to retrieve
            the currently-selected domain-specific external documents from the currently-viewed/edited CMS document in the context.
          </li>
          <li>
            When the plugin needs to display the linked external documents (e.g, title),
            it invokes the <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> with the current document context.
            The <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> should give a proper title string for your domain-specific document object to the plugin.
          </li>
          <li>
            The <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a> instance is invoked from the External Document Field Browser Dialog in order to
            search domain-specific external documents and display document information such as title, description and icon in the dialog.
          </li>
        </ul>
        <img src="../images/exdocpickerbase-archview.png" alt="Architectural View" />
        <p>
          See <a href="../apidocs/index.html">Javadocs</a> for detail about the <a href="apidocs/org/onehippo/forge/exdocpicker/api/ExternalDocumentServiceFacade.html" target="_blank">ExternalSearchServiceFacade</a>.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
